All right, it is time to make a request
from our code. So there is a function
for this. And so in your script tag,
write the keyword fetch. And inside of
there, um, it takes a URL that you want
to make a request to. So if I want to
make a request to the same one I made to
before, I'll say https colash. So, I'm
going to make an HTTP request and I'm
going to go out over the internet and I
want to go to api.advice
slip. Sorry, make sure I spell
everything right.
So, we know that that will give us back
an object, but it doesn't directly give
us back an object because this takes
time. What does fetch return? You
guessed it, it returns a promise. So um
there are two ways that we could handle
this and I'm going to demonstrate both
of them. So first demonstrate my
favorite. So you can write an async
function. So I'll call async get data
and um
I do need to use the word function.
So, async
get data
and then in here
I'm going to await that fetch and I'm
going to store it. So, I'm going to say
let response equal
await fetch. And then now on the next
line I can console.log log
the response
or if you like to chain then um oh I do
need to call my get data I never
remember to do that um or you can take
this line here
and I'll paste it below and you can say
fetch and then once you've gone out and
fetched it then take the response that
you were given and log it.
So line 20 and lines 11 through 18 do
the same thing. So we'll save this and
we'll go live.
Oh, sorry. One second.
And if we inspect this page here on the
console, we can see we got response and
response. So, let's open up this first
response. And you can see the URL we
sent it to. Um, and you can see that we
did in fact get a good response. And if
you're familiar with HTTP status codes,
we get the status code. There's all
sorts of information in this response.
The one that I really want to point your
attention to is this body. Notice that
it has dot dot dot here. And if I click
on it, it says that the body is a
readable stream. What is a readable
stream? Well, it is a stream of
information coming back from wherever
you requested it. And it can take some
time to read this stream. And if I want
to read this stream and put it into a
variable in my code, it can take some
time. And if it's going to take some
time, what does that mean we're dealing
with? You guessed it. We're dealing with
another promise.